Why does an organization do a project.
Well that question is called the project initiation context.
We'll see it again coming up.
The reason why projects are generally selected why an organization does a project.
Is there some business value for initiating a project for investing the time and the money and the resources
into the effort to create that unique product service condition or result.
Well that value is called business value a business.
Now you describe the benefits for the organization or the stakeholders or the customers of the project.
So organizations do projects because projects enable business value.
There are two types of business now you have tangible business value.
And of course intangible tangibles easy to see we're talking about things you get new fixtures or equipment
or hardware software money you get you get a profit from the project you get a market share your stakeholders
get some equity.
So it's all those those good things you can touch and feel and there's utility to that money or to that
equity or what have you.
So those are tangible now in tangible business now you are things like Goodwill and reputation in the
community or in the marketplace.
Brand recognition is there's a public benefit so it's like a not for profit or a project that was done
for the community.
So there's a public benefit could be trademarks or strategic alignment.
So those are intangible hard to quantify the value of brand recognition.
So but you could do a project to increase your brand recognition.
But that's business now you will see business value a couple times throughout the course.
Generally business value is described in a document called the business case.
The business case of course describes why do we want to do this project.
Why do we want to invest in it.
So what is the return on investment.
And that's where we described business now the work that your project creates for the organization.
All right great job.
Keep moving forward.